Prepare for the coming.
Lord of Illusions is a horror, fantasy, drama film directed by Clive Barker.
During a routine case in L.A., NY private investigator Harry D'Amour stumbles over members of a fanatic cult who are
preparing for the resurrection of their leader Nix, a powerful magician who was killed 13 years earlier.
Harry D'Amour, played by Scott Bakula.
Philip Swann, played by Kevin J. O'Connor.
Dorothea Swann, played by Famke Janssen.
Valentin, played by Joel Swetow.
Nix, played by Daniel von Bargen.
Butterfield, played by Barry Del Sherman.
Lord of Illusions is a 1995 American neo-noir supernatural horror film written and directed by Clive Barker, based
on his own short story The Last Illusion published in 1985 in the anthology Books of Blood Volume 6.
The same story introduced Barker's occult detective Harry D'Amour, who
later appeared in several prose stories and comic books.
Lord of Illusions is D'Amour's first onscreen appearance, with
the character portrayed by actor Scott Bakula.
Other actors appearing in the film include Kevin J.
O'Connor, Famke Janssen and Daniel von Bargen.
The story features D'Amour, who has had several experiences with the supernatural, embarking on an
investigation involving a stage illusionist named Swann and a cult led by a sorcerer named Nix.
Although Clive Barker decided to keep a few story elements and the same principal characters from "The Last Illusion", he otherwise
presented a new story for the movie and created a new villain, surprising several readers familiar with the original work.
The film met with mixed reception and no further live-action
movies featuring Harry D'Amour were made.
The film explores themes of supernatural, fanatic, resurrection, occult, sect.
The tone is dark and emotional.